

Samuel Godfried Katiandagho, SST, MM

Place, Date of birth : Jakarta, 22 March 1983

Address : Jl. Poltangan No. 23 RT. 003/ RW. 05

Tanjung Barat, Jagakarsa, Jakarta Selatan 12530

Mobile phone : (+62) 81280000238 Email : godfrieds@yahoo.com

CAREER OBJECTIVE

To earn a management position in the sales & marketing and compassionately lead a creative team utilizing my professional experience and educational background.

PERSONAL PROFILE

Reliable, Enthusiastic, Hardworking, Independent, Quick learner, Target oriented, Good presentation skill, Excellence communication and sales skill, Self radiant with the ability to remain calm, Experience and capable to work under pressure, Enjoy working on own initiative and as part of a team.

EDUCATION

Magister Management, Universitas Trisakti Jakarta	2008-2011
Majoring Marketing Management	
Sekolah Tinggi Pariwisata Trisakti Jakarta	2005-2011
Majoring Tourism Management – Hotel, GPA: 3.58/4.00 (Cum Laude)	
SMU Negeri 3, Jakarta	1998-2001

TRAINING & COURSES

Marketing Strategic By Philp Kotler, Mark Plus	2011
How To Become Proactive Sales, Dunamis	2010
English Course, LIA, Basic Level-Advanced Level	1999-2001
English Course, ILP, Basic Level	1998-1999

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Berita Satu Media Holdings
Deputy General Manager, Sales & Event
SUARA PEMBARUAN (DIGITAL & NEWSPAPER)
April 2013 – present

August 2011-November 2015

 Responsible for advertising & event sales of digital (suarapembaruan.com) and print (Suara Pembaruan Newspaper)

- Event concept (For a Better Indonesia 2014, Green & Culture Festival 2015, Indonesian Young Leader)
- Marketing Strategy to maintain brand awareness of Suara Pembaruan (client gathering and entertainment, advertising at others media in group)
- Planning, organizing, controlling sales process and evaluating team performance
- Assisting GM Sales to lead a team of 3 Managers, and 10 Account Executives. Besides, handling my own Special Project team of 5 Account Executives
- Responsible for increasing sales revenue through special projects strategy, such as: Special issue Program, Co-Branding Program, Events, and other revenue channels
- Report to General Manager Sales
- Achievement: Sales (2014) increment 60% compare to previous year (2013) Establishing new advertising product

Head of Advertising & Event for CAMPUS LIFE MAGAZINE (Sales & Marketing Division) August 2011 – March 2013

- · Reported to Chief Operation Officer, Commercial Director, and Editor in Chief
- Managing a team of 2 Account Managers, 4 Account Executives, 1
 Business Development personnel, 1 Event Coordinator
- Lead the division of Sales Advertising (Printed and Online) and Event
- Created Business Plan & Strategic Planning for sales team
- Created Key Performance Indicator for sales team projects and routines
- Responsible to develop business, from nonprofit to high profit
- Monitored business flow and evaluation
- 2012 achievements
 - 1. Event organizing (concept, presentation, and implementation)
 - Media Gathering "Introducing CAMPUS LIFE MAGAZINE"
 - Insurepreneurship with LIPPO INSURANCE
 - FUN BIKE with CEOs
 - Preparing Your Children for HARVARD with Jasson Ma
 - Campus Face 2012 (Campus Roadshow, Quarantine, Grand Final)
 - WORLD EDUCATION EXPO INDONESIA 2013
 - 2. Increased brand awareness, market share for circulation and advertising

Media Indonesia - Media Group

May 2006-August 2011

Daily newspaper, mediaindonesia.com

Account Manager

- Reported to Advertising Division Head and Business Development Director
- Created **Business Plan & Strategic Planning** for sales team activities in 1 year, to achieve a team target of Rp. 3 billion
- Created Key Performance Indicator of sales team for projects & routines activities
- Lead a team of 1 Senior Account Executive, 2 Madya Account Executives, and 1 Junior Account Executive
- Earned the highest team target and highest percentage of achievement for year 2010 and Q1 in 2011

- Opened sales network to nationwide advertising agencies and direct clients
- Maintained existing clients and encouraged them to spend more on Media Indonesia
- Presented and collaborated products with Metro TV, mediaindonesia.com, publishing (magazines) and various event organizer
- · Daily, weekly, and monthly sales review report
- Monitored clients progress and competitor updates

Client specialization:

- Telecommunications: XL, TELKOM, Telkomsel, SMARTFREN, AXIS, Indosat
- Internet Provider: CBN, Centrin, 3GNET, Telkomselflash, Speedy, etc.
- Electronics (home appliances and IT): ASUS, Toshiba, ACER, SAMSUNG
- Airlines: Garuda Indonesia, Singapore Airlines, Malaysia Airlines, Tiger, CITILINK
- Government institutions
- Hotels and Restaurants nationwide
- Leisure & Tourism Destination: Snowbay, Taman Safari Indonesia, Waterboom, etc
- Embassy: The Netherlands
- Pay TV: Indovision, Telkomvision, Skynindo, Central TV, Aura TV

Senior Account Executive

- Assisted Account Manager and performed as a role model to junior Account Executives
- Conducted telemarketing, presentation and network building between Media Indonesia and its clients (prospective and existing clients): agencies and direct clients, maintained positive relationship in the long run and monitored competitors' activities
- **Achievement:** The Highest Achievement during 2 years (average more than 100%), compared to other Account Executives, thus, earning promotion to Account Manager

Junior Account Executive

- Responsible for earning target of Rp. 6 billion/year
- Telemarketing, presenting and approaching prospective and existing client

MYBODY GYM & SPA

2005-2006

Health gym club and health care center

Corporate Marketing Communication

- Developed operate image through both above-the-line and below-the-line methods
- Prepared and presented annual Marketing and Public Relations Plan
- Conducted promotion campaign activity (advertisement placement, advertorial, editorial, media coverage, promotion tools, press release and photo caption)
- Activation (MyBodyGym 123 bowling competition)
- Media Relations
- **Achievement:** free Media coverage, average amount of Rp. 3 Billion worth of campaign in TV, Newspaper, Magazine, and Radio

STARBUCKS COFFEE INDONESIA

2003-2005

Food and Beverage service, specialty in coffee

Barista

• Operational responsibilities to increase sales by doing up-selling product, implementing smart advertising (coffee sampling), customer service.

ASTON HOTEL JAKARTA

2003-2004

5 star serviced-apartment

Sales & Marketing Trainee

- Learned and practiced sales calls and conducted sales blitz for corporate accounts
- Prepared and finalized weekly and monthly sales and marketing reports
- Assisted the Public Relations Manager in various ad-hoc activities

REFERENCES

Stephanie Riady, Owner & Founder Agora Exhibition **Kiki Subarkah**, Director Sales & Marketing, MNC Group **Nieke P Handayani**, Public Relation Manager Aston Hotel Sudirman **Listyorini**, Deputy Director Berita Satu Media Holdings *Contact details will be given upon request